PAUL CARON

404-667-3528 □ paulcaron247@gmail.com □ www.linkedin.com/in/paulcaronnews □ Paulcaronnews.com

SUMMARY

Award-winning Senior Manager and Journalist with experience building and managing successful teams in a network newsroom and on site at major news stories. The experience is diverse: news room manager, desk manager, bureau manager, correspondent and field producer with crisis management skills. The strengths include working across various platforms, collaborating with show teams, bureaus and field personnel, and bringing it all together for award winning news coverage. Recognized for industry knowledge, ability to manage in crisis situations and mentoring of staff to exceed goals.

Successful Team Leader Team Builder Deep Industry Knowledge Highly Respected News Judgment Crisis Management Skills Steady Navigator In Times Of Change

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CNN, Atlanta, GA 1986-2014

National Content Center Manager (2012-2014)

Supervised, led and managed editors for regions that cover the U.S. and Canada finding, developing breaking news, for television, digital and social media. Led breaking news coverage, including guidance for all platforms, assigning reporting team assignments including satellite trucks and other live technology. Delegated work breakdown, using news judgment, story development and factoring in business costs.

- Piloted first integration of CNN newsgathering sources and social media teams, which became the corporate standard.
- Oversaw finding 3rd party video and photo images for all CNN platforms, increasing usage especially during breaking news.
- Improved and increased news 'alerts' by 65% by melding newsgathering efforts on CNN Digital Team.
- Developed strategy to work closely with Affiliate Desk managers and editors, in lock-step during developing and breaking news, improving relations with CNN affiliate stations.
- Acted as final approval for editor's news alerts, breaking news and developments to all CNN platforms ensuring accuracy and consistency.
- Led planning with digital editors and show executive producers for on-air shows based on timing factors and special considerations.
- Recognized as a successful team lead and mentor with editors requesting to work under supervision.
- Piloted and managed five CNN Twitter accounts obtaining 20,000 followers.
- Recognized as most trusted replacement for Director of Coverage earning high marks from executive producers for attention to detail.
- Improved relationship between CNN, Headline News and CNN International allowing shared resources and decreased expenses.

Regional Assignment Desk Manager (2004-2012)

Managed editorial planning and coverage for all day-to-day and breaking news situations, including successful coverage of Jerry Sandusky scandal, Newtown school shootings, and other stories. Expanded responsibility to include Northeast Region & Southeast Region Desk Manager and Senior Assignment Editor, CNN National Desk; also Director of Coverage.

- Oversaw NE desk editor-affiliate relations, improving CNN affiliate relations, leading to increase in affiliate collaboration and renewals.
- Won three Peabody awards for managing excellent coverage during Arab Spring, Gulf Oil Spills and Hurricane Katrina.

PAUL CARON
Page Two

CNN (Continued)

Political Desk Manager (2008)

Brought in the middle of the national campaign to manage, oversee and direct the desk and coverage of historic Presidential campaign, including Democratic and Republican Conventions and Election Day.

- Installed new budget tracking to assign costs to shows and platforms allowing decrease in expenses and duplication of efforts.
- Managed partnership with NBC to pool resources on campaign events and debates decreasing overall costs.
- Won two Emmys and a Peabody Award for exceptional political coverage.

Weekend News Manager (CNN National Desk) / Sr. Assignment Editor (1997-2004)

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts Degree, double major: Journalism and Broadcast and Cinematic Arts, Central Michigan University

ADDITIONAL HIGHLIGHTS

- Planned, built and managed makeshift bureau in Tallahassee for Florida recount of Presidential Election 2000.
- Miami Bureau manager, led staff of 18 employees; assistant bureau chief duties, and correspondent, including reporting in Cuba, Dominican Republic, Haiti, hurricanes and Space Shuttle launches/landings.
- London Bureau correspondent, field and control room producer-reported on resignation of UK Prime Minister Margaret Thatcher, IRA bombings in London and impact of Gulf War on Europe.
- Produced coverage of major plane crashes, including Detroit/Northwest Airlines Flight 255 and the survival of four year old Cecelia Cichan, and crash of United Airlines Flight 232 in Iowa.
- Closely covered the auto industry in Detroit, the Midwest and Europe.

PUBLICATIONS

CNN.com reported stories at http://www.paulcaronnews.com/

AWARDS & RECOGNITIONS

2011 Peabody Award for coverage of the Arab Spring2010 Peabody Award for coverage of Gulf Oil Spill

2008 Emmy Award for coverage of Democratic Convention

2008 Emmy Award for coverage of Election Day

2008 Peabody Award for coverage of 2008 Presidential primary, campaigns and debates.

2005 Alfred I. Dupont-Columbia University Award for coverage of tsunami disaster in South Asia

2005 Peabody Award for coverage of Hurricane Katrina

2001 Special Emmy Award for coverage of 9/11 Attacks

Member CNN Diversity Council

Assisted and commended by FBI, in helping find kidnapped Mich. youth in Florida.